mirrorlink.com 2016-11-04

# MirrorLink

Car Connectivity Consortium LLC ("Car Connectivity " or "We") is committed to user privacy in our products and services. This online privacy policy outlines our information-handling practices for both personal information and non-personally identifiable information for the [www.mirrorlink.com](http://www.mirrorlink.com/) and [www.carconnectivity.org](http://www.carconnectivity.org/) websites (collectively, the “Site” or "Car Connectivity Website"). This policy applies only to transactions with, and information gathered from, the Car Connectivity Website and related services, and does not apply to activities unrelated to the Car Connectivity Website. By using the Car Connectivity Website, you agree to accept the practices and terms set forth in this privacy policy. We encourage you to read this privacy policy and those of all websites that you visit.

For each visitor to Car Connectivity’s Site, Car Connectivity’s Web server may recognize, collect and/or store information such as the visitor’s IP address/domain name combination, and any referring sites to keep track of the origin of our visitors and other non-personally-identifiable information, that will help administer the Car Connectivity Website and to help diagnose any problems that may occur with our server. The non-personally identifiable information we may gather includes the type of browser that you use and IP address, the content that you access and the length of your visit to the Car Connectivity Website. Car Connectivity uses this information, typically in aggregate form, to improve the operation of the Car Connectivity Website and organization, analyze interest in the areas of the Car Connectivity Website and to personalize and similarly tailor content displayed to users. We may also release aggregate information about user trends to partners and other third parties. An example of this type of information would be patterns of use of the Car Connectivity Website based on geography or industry. We also retain aggregated log files of requested content in order to report overall usage and to evaluate user trends. If you wish to be removed from our email reports list, click on the link to “unsubscribe” at the bottom of any message and you will be immediately unsubscribed.

While we do not generally require you to provide us with personally identifiable information in order to visit and use our Site, in order to participate in some activities, such as becoming a Car Connectivity Member or requesting information about Car Connectivity, it is necessary for you to provide this information. Web-based forms on our site may require users to give us contact information (like their name, company, mailing address, email address, and telephone number). We use contact information from these forms to send the user information about Car Connectivity and may follow up with further mailings. We do not collect any personal information, including your email address, without your prior knowledge and consent. Car Connectivity does not sell to advertiser(s) any personally identifying information that you submit. You always have the choice to opt-out of any future mailing. By using this website, you consent to the collection and use of this information as described herein. You may also be asked to provide personally identifiable information in order to use certain portions of the Car Connectivity Website and to obtain maintenance and support from Car Connectivity, if Car Connectivity elects to provide any. This information may include your name, address, telephone number, company and e-mail address. If you do not wish to provide Car Connectivity with any personally identifiable information, you should cease using that portion of the Car Connectivity Website.

### Cookies and other Information Collection

The Car Connectivity Website uses “cookies”. Cookies help provide a better user experience by storing useful information about the user to provide easier access when the user returns, and to enable us to measure which website areas are of greatest interest. Some pages on our Site may use cookies so that we can recall who you are when you revisit the Site or when you fill out a Web application, and will remember you, providing you with easier access to Website user areas, or to track your preferences to improve your Site experience. We may also compile statistical data from data derived from cookies on your use of our Site. You may decline the cookie by modifying the appropriate settings in your Web browser; however, although you will still be able to access our website, please note that disabling cookies may impede you from taking advantage of certain features on the Site.

The Car Connectivity Website may display advertisements from third parties. Third party advertisers decide which ads are shown. These advertisers may use cookies to collect non-personally identifiable information from our Site visitors. Advertisers use this information to target the ads to their audience and to evaluate their impact.

Car Connectivity may use personally identifying information:

To send you notices and updates relating to your membership in Car Connectivity  
To send you news, updates and special offers from Car Connectivity. You may remove yourself from this list at any time by e-mailing us as provided below.  
To manage your account and account access, provide you with support, at our discretion, and to keep track of support requests.  
To enforce intellectual property rights related to the Car Connectivity Specification and Marks

Car Connectivity may disclose personally identifiable information to third parties to: (i) provide technical support, respond to questions, resolve problems and correct errors with regard to the Car Connectivity Website and Car Connectivity Specification; (ii) to offer Certification Program services with regard to the Terminal Mode specification; (iii) to enhance your experience in connection with the Car Connectivity Website and Terminal Mode Specification, and (iv) to enforce Car Connectivity’s Terminal Mode Specification and related Marks. Car Connectivity may also share personally identifiable information with Car Connectivity agents, representatives, contractors, and service providers in order to provide the Car Connectivity Website and related services. By using the Car Connectivity Website you consent to our sharing your personally identifiable information with third parties in connection with delivering the Car Connectivity Website and the content on the Site. Due to our contractual obligations with these third parties and the need to share personally identifiable information to deliver and support the Car Connectivity Website, we may not provide you with the opportunity to opt-out of sharing personally identifiable information with these third parties and still receive complete access to the Car Connectivity Website and related services. Your personally identifiable information may be provided to a third party if Car Connectivity files for bankruptcy, or there is a transfer of the assets or ownership of Car Connectivity, Car Connectivity may also disclose personally identifiable information in order to respond to a subpoena, court order or other such request. Car Connectivity may also provide such personally identifiable information order to comply with law or in response to a law enforcement agency's request, to enforce our privacy policy and end user agreements or to protect the rights, property or safety of the Car Connectivity Website, users of the services and others.

The Car Connectivity Website may offer links to third party sites. Since Car Connectivity does not control or operate these third party websites, we are not responsible for the privacy policies of websites and services to which the Car Connectivity Website may link. If you provide any information to such third parties, different rules regarding the collection and use of your personal information may apply. We strongly recommend that you review such third party's privacy policies before providing any data to them.

Car Connectivity takes appropriate steps to ensure data privacy and security including through various hardware and software methodologies. However, due to the open communication nature of the Internet, we cannot guarantee that communications between you and the Car Connectivity Website, and the Car Connectivity Website and you, will be free from unauthorized access by third parties. Users of the Car Connectivity Website do so at their own risk. Car Connectivity cannot guarantee the security of any information that is disclosed online.

We will use reasonable efforts to comply with this privacy policy and will take prompt corrective action when we learn of any failure to comply with our privacy policy. We sometimes release beta versions of our website and related services, which are further refined before the release of the final version. Because the website and services are still in a test phase, we may not always catch an unintended privacy issue, despite our efforts to do so. As such, we welcome user feedback on any privacy concerns you may have. In light of the above and because of the complex and constantly changing nature of the internet and related technology, Car Connectivity does not guarantee error-free performance under this privacy policy. To the extent permissible under law, Car Connectivity and third parties providing services to you in connection with the Car Connectivity Website, shall not be liable for any incidental, consequential or punitive damages relating to this privacy policy.

Car Connectivity does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. Car Connectivity requests that children under the age of 13 not use the Car Connectivity Website nor submit any personal information to the Car Connectivity Website. Since information regarding children under the age of 13 is not collected, Car Connectivity does not knowingly use or distribute personal information regarding children under the age of 13. If Car Connectivity obtains actual knowledge that it has collected personal information about a child under the age of 13, that information will be immediately deleted from our database.

If you wish to: (i) remove your personally identifiable information from our database in order to stop receiving information from us, (ii) update your personal information, or (iii) have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this website, you can contact:

Car Connectivity Consortium Administration  
3855 SW 153rd Drive  
Beaverton, OR 97006  
USA  
Attention: Car Connectivity Website Administrator  
Email: [admin@carconnectivity.org](mailto:admin@carconnectivity.org)

Car Connectivity reserves the rights to modify its privacy policy at any time and will notify you by posting an amendment to the privacy policy on the Car Connectivity Website. Such modifications will become effective on the day they are posted. Car Connectivity encourages you to frequently review the privacy policy for any modifications.  
25390354\V-1

Car Connectivity Consortium LLC ("Car Connectivity " or "We") is committed to user privacy in our products and services. This online privacy policy outlines our information-handling practices for both personal information and non-personally identifiable information for the [www.mirrorlink.com](http://www.mirrorlink.com/) and [www.carconnectivity.org](http://www.carconnectivity.org/) websites (collectively, the “Site” or "Car Connectivity Website"). This policy applies only to transactions with, and information gathered from, the Car Connectivity Website and related services, and does not apply to activities unrelated to the Car Connectivity Website. By using the Car Connectivity Website, you agree to accept the practices and terms set forth in this privacy policy. We encourage you to read this privacy policy and those of all websites that you visit.

For each visitor to Car Connectivity’s Site, Car Connectivity’s Web server may recognize, collect and/or store information such as the visitor’s IP address/domain name combination, and any referring sites to keep track of the origin of our visitors and other non-personally-identifiable information, that will help administer the Car Connectivity Website and to help diagnose any problems that may occur with our server. The non-personally identifiable information we may gather includes the type of browser that you use and IP address, the content that you access and the length of your visit to the Car Connectivity Website. Car Connectivity uses this information, typically in aggregate form, to improve the operation of the Car Connectivity Website and organization, analyze interest in the areas of the Car Connectivity Website and to personalize and similarly tailor content displayed to users. We may also release aggregate information about user trends to partners and other third parties. An example of this type of information would be patterns of use of the Car Connectivity Website based on geography or industry. We also retain aggregated log files of requested content in order to report overall usage and to evaluate user trends. If you wish to be removed from our email reports list, click on the link to “unsubscribe” at the bottom of any message and you will be immediately unsubscribed.

While we do not generally require you to provide us with personally identifiable information in order to visit and use our Site, in order to participate in some activities, such as becoming a Car Connectivity Member or requesting information about Car Connectivity, it is necessary for you to provide this information. Web-based forms on our site may require users to give us contact information (like their name, company, mailing address, email address, and telephone number). We use contact information from these forms to send the user information about Car Connectivity and may follow up with further mailings. We do not collect any personal information, including your email address, without your prior knowledge and consent. Car Connectivity does not sell to advertiser(s) any personally identifying information that you submit. You always have the choice to opt-out of any future mailing. By using this website, you consent to the collection and use of this information as described herein. You may also be asked to provide personally identifiable information in order to use certain portions of the Car Connectivity Website and to obtain maintenance and support from Car Connectivity, if Car Connectivity elects to provide any. This information may include your name, address, telephone number, company and e-mail address. If you do not wish to provide Car Connectivity with any personally identifiable information, you should cease using that portion of the Car Connectivity Website.

### Cookies and other Information Collection

The Car Connectivity Website uses “cookies”. Cookies help provide a better user experience by storing useful information about the user to provide easier access when the user returns, and to enable us to measure which website areas are of greatest interest. Some pages on our Site may use cookies so that we can recall who you are when you revisit the Site or when you fill out a Web application, and will remember you, providing you with easier access to Website user areas, or to track your preferences to improve your Site experience. We may also compile statistical data from data derived from cookies on your use of our Site. You may decline the cookie by modifying the appropriate settings in your Web browser; however, although you will still be able to access our website, please note that disabling cookies may impede you from taking advantage of certain features on the Site.

The Car Connectivity Website may display advertisements from third parties. Third party advertisers decide which ads are shown. These advertisers may use cookies to collect non-personally identifiable information from our Site visitors. Advertisers use this information to target the ads to their audience and to evaluate their impact.

Car Connectivity may use personally identifying information:

To send you notices and updates relating to your membership in Car Connectivity  
To send you news, updates and special offers from Car Connectivity. You may remove yourself from this list at any time by e-mailing us as provided below.  
To manage your account and account access, provide you with support, at our discretion, and to keep track of support requests.  
To enforce intellectual property rights related to the Car Connectivity Specification and Marks

Car Connectivity may disclose personally identifiable information to third parties to: (i) provide technical support, respond to questions, resolve problems and correct errors with regard to the Car Connectivity Website and Car Connectivity Specification; (ii) to offer Certification Program services with regard to the Terminal Mode specification; (iii) to enhance your experience in connection with the Car Connectivity Website and Terminal Mode Specification, and (iv) to enforce Car Connectivity’s Terminal Mode Specification and related Marks. Car Connectivity may also share personally identifiable information with Car Connectivity agents, representatives, contractors, and service providers in order to provide the Car Connectivity Website and related services. By using the Car Connectivity Website you consent to our sharing your personally identifiable information with third parties in connection with delivering the Car Connectivity Website and the content on the Site. Due to our contractual obligations with these third parties and the need to share personally identifiable information to deliver and support the Car Connectivity Website, we may not provide you with the opportunity to opt-out of sharing personally identifiable information with these third parties and still receive complete access to the Car Connectivity Website and related services. Your personally identifiable information may be provided to a third party if Car Connectivity files for bankruptcy, or there is a transfer of the assets or ownership of Car Connectivity, Car Connectivity may also disclose personally identifiable information in order to respond to a subpoena, court order or other such request. Car Connectivity may also provide such personally identifiable information order to comply with law or in response to a law enforcement agency's request, to enforce our privacy policy and end user agreements or to protect the rights, property or safety of the Car Connectivity Website, users of the services and others.

The Car Connectivity Website may offer links to third party sites. Since Car Connectivity does not control or operate these third party websites, we are not responsible for the privacy policies of websites and services to which the Car Connectivity Website may link. If you provide any information to such third parties, different rules regarding the collection and use of your personal information may apply. We strongly recommend that you review such third party's privacy policies before providing any data to them.

Car Connectivity takes appropriate steps to ensure data privacy and security including through various hardware and software methodologies. However, due to the open communication nature of the Internet, we cannot guarantee that communications between you and the Car Connectivity Website, and the Car Connectivity Website and you, will be free from unauthorized access by third parties. Users of the Car Connectivity Website do so at their own risk. Car Connectivity cannot guarantee the security of any information that is disclosed online.

We will use reasonable efforts to comply with this privacy policy and will take prompt corrective action when we learn of any failure to comply with our privacy policy. We sometimes release beta versions of our website and related services, which are further refined before the release of the final version. Because the website and services are still in a test phase, we may not always catch an unintended privacy issue, despite our efforts to do so. As such, we welcome user feedback on any privacy concerns you may have. In light of the above and because of the complex and constantly changing nature of the internet and related technology, Car Connectivity does not guarantee error-free performance under this privacy policy. To the extent permissible under law, Car Connectivity and third parties providing services to you in connection with the Car Connectivity Website, shall not be liable for any incidental, consequential or punitive damages relating to this privacy policy.

Car Connectivity does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. Car Connectivity requests that children under the age of 13 not use the Car Connectivity Website nor submit any personal information to the Car Connectivity Website. Since information regarding children under the age of 13 is not collected, Car Connectivity does not knowingly use or distribute personal information regarding children under the age of 13. If Car Connectivity obtains actual knowledge that it has collected personal information about a child under the age of 13, that information will be immediately deleted from our database.

If you wish to: (i) remove your personally identifiable information from our database in order to stop receiving information from us, (ii) update your personal information, or (iii) have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this website, you can contact:

Car Connectivity Consortium Administration  
3855 SW 153rd Drive  
Beaverton, OR 97006  
USA  
Attention: Car Connectivity Website Administrator  
Email: [admin@carconnectivity.org](mailto:admin@carconnectivity.org)

Car Connectivity reserves the rights to modify its privacy policy at any time and will notify you by posting an amendment to the privacy policy on the Car Connectivity Website. Such modifications will become effective on the day they are posted. Car Connectivity encourages you to frequently review the privacy policy for any modifications.  
25390354\V-1

Car Connectivity Consortium LLC ("Car Connectivity " or "We") is committed to user privacy in our products and services. This online privacy policy outlines our information-handling practices for both personal information and non-personally identifiable information for the [www.mirrorlink.com](http://www.mirrorlink.com/) and [www.carconnectivity.org](http://www.carconnectivity.org/) websites (collectively, the “Site” or "Car Connectivity Website"). This policy applies only to transactions with, and information gathered from, the Car Connectivity Website and related services, and does not apply to activities unrelated to the Car Connectivity Website. By using the Car Connectivity Website, you agree to accept the practices and terms set forth in this privacy policy. We encourage you to read this privacy policy and those of all websites that you visit.

For each visitor to Car Connectivity’s Site, Car Connectivity’s Web server may recognize, collect and/or store information such as the visitor’s IP address/domain name combination, and any referring sites to keep track of the origin of our visitors and other non-personally-identifiable information, that will help administer the Car Connectivity Website and to help diagnose any problems that may occur with our server. The non-personally identifiable information we may gather includes the type of browser that you use and IP address, the content that you access and the length of your visit to the Car Connectivity Website. Car Connectivity uses this information, typically in aggregate form, to improve the operation of the Car Connectivity Website and organization, analyze interest in the areas of the Car Connectivity Website and to personalize and similarly tailor content displayed to users. We may also release aggregate information about user trends to partners and other third parties. An example of this type of information would be patterns of use of the Car Connectivity Website based on geography or industry. We also retain aggregated log files of requested content in order to report overall usage and to evaluate user trends. If you wish to be removed from our email reports list, click on the link to “unsubscribe” at the bottom of any message and you will be immediately unsubscribed.

While we do not generally require you to provide us with personally identifiable information in order to visit and use our Site, in order to participate in some activities, such as becoming a Car Connectivity Member or requesting information about Car Connectivity, it is necessary for you to provide this information. Web-based forms on our site may require users to give us contact information (like their name, company, mailing address, email address, and telephone number). We use contact information from these forms to send the user information about Car Connectivity and may follow up with further mailings. We do not collect any personal information, including your email address, without your prior knowledge and consent. Car Connectivity does not sell to advertiser(s) any personally identifying information that you submit. You always have the choice to opt-out of any future mailing. By using this website, you consent to the collection and use of this information as described herein. You may also be asked to provide personally identifiable information in order to use certain portions of the Car Connectivity Website and to obtain maintenance and support from Car Connectivity, if Car Connectivity elects to provide any. This information may include your name, address, telephone number, company and e-mail address. If you do not wish to provide Car Connectivity with any personally identifiable information, you should cease using that portion of the Car Connectivity Website.

### Cookies and other Information Collection

The Car Connectivity Website uses “cookies”. Cookies help provide a better user experience by storing useful information about the user to provide easier access when the user returns, and to enable us to measure which website areas are of greatest interest. Some pages on our Site may use cookies so that we can recall who you are when you revisit the Site or when you fill out a Web application, and will remember you, providing you with easier access to Website user areas, or to track your preferences to improve your Site experience. We may also compile statistical data from data derived from cookies on your use of our Site. You may decline the cookie by modifying the appropriate settings in your Web browser; however, although you will still be able to access our website, please note that disabling cookies may impede you from taking advantage of certain features on the Site.

The Car Connectivity Website may display advertisements from third parties. Third party advertisers decide which ads are shown. These advertisers may use cookies to collect non-personally identifiable information from our Site visitors. Advertisers use this information to target the ads to their audience and to evaluate their impact.

Car Connectivity may use personally identifying information:

To send you notices and updates relating to your membership in Car Connectivity  
To send you news, updates and special offers from Car Connectivity. You may remove yourself from this list at any time by e-mailing us as provided below.  
To manage your account and account access, provide you with support, at our discretion, and to keep track of support requests.  
To enforce intellectual property rights related to the Car Connectivity Specification and Marks

Car Connectivity may disclose personally identifiable information to third parties to: (i) provide technical support, respond to questions, resolve problems and correct errors with regard to the Car Connectivity Website and Car Connectivity Specification; (ii) to offer Certification Program services with regard to the Terminal Mode specification; (iii) to enhance your experience in connection with the Car Connectivity Website and Terminal Mode Specification, and (iv) to enforce Car Connectivity’s Terminal Mode Specification and related Marks. Car Connectivity may also share personally identifiable information with Car Connectivity agents, representatives, contractors, and service providers in order to provide the Car Connectivity Website and related services. By using the Car Connectivity Website you consent to our sharing your personally identifiable information with third parties in connection with delivering the Car Connectivity Website and the content on the Site. Due to our contractual obligations with these third parties and the need to share personally identifiable information to deliver and support the Car Connectivity Website, we may not provide you with the opportunity to opt-out of sharing personally identifiable information with these third parties and still receive complete access to the Car Connectivity Website and related services. Your personally identifiable information may be provided to a third party if Car Connectivity files for bankruptcy, or there is a transfer of the assets or ownership of Car Connectivity, Car Connectivity may also disclose personally identifiable information in order to respond to a subpoena, court order or other such request. Car Connectivity may also provide such personally identifiable information order to comply with law or in response to a law enforcement agency's request, to enforce our privacy policy and end user agreements or to protect the rights, property or safety of the Car Connectivity Website, users of the services and others.

The Car Connectivity Website may offer links to third party sites. Since Car Connectivity does not control or operate these third party websites, we are not responsible for the privacy policies of websites and services to which the Car Connectivity Website may link. If you provide any information to such third parties, different rules regarding the collection and use of your personal information may apply. We strongly recommend that you review such third party's privacy policies before providing any data to them.

Car Connectivity takes appropriate steps to ensure data privacy and security including through various hardware and software methodologies. However, due to the open communication nature of the Internet, we cannot guarantee that communications between you and the Car Connectivity Website, and the Car Connectivity Website and you, will be free from unauthorized access by third parties. Users of the Car Connectivity Website do so at their own risk. Car Connectivity cannot guarantee the security of any information that is disclosed online.

We will use reasonable efforts to comply with this privacy policy and will take prompt corrective action when we learn of any failure to comply with our privacy policy. We sometimes release beta versions of our website and related services, which are further refined before the release of the final version. Because the website and services are still in a test phase, we may not always catch an unintended privacy issue, despite our efforts to do so. As such, we welcome user feedback on any privacy concerns you may have. In light of the above and because of the complex and constantly changing nature of the internet and related technology, Car Connectivity does not guarantee error-free performance under this privacy policy. To the extent permissible under law, Car Connectivity and third parties providing services to you in connection with the Car Connectivity Website, shall not be liable for any incidental, consequential or punitive damages relating to this privacy policy.

Car Connectivity does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. Car Connectivity requests that children under the age of 13 not use the Car Connectivity Website nor submit any personal information to the Car Connectivity Website. Since information regarding children under the age of 13 is not collected, Car Connectivity does not knowingly use or distribute personal information regarding children under the age of 13. If Car Connectivity obtains actual knowledge that it has collected personal information about a child under the age of 13, that information will be immediately deleted from our database.

If you wish to: (i) remove your personally identifiable information from our database in order to stop receiving information from us, (ii) update your personal information, or (iii) have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this website, you can contact:

Car Connectivity Consortium Administration  
3855 SW 153rd Drive  
Beaverton, OR 97006  
USA  
Attention: Car Connectivity Website Administrator  
Email: [admin@carconnectivity.org](mailto:admin@carconnectivity.org)

Car Connectivity reserves the rights to modify its privacy policy at any time and will notify you by posting an amendment to the privacy policy on the Car Connectivity Website. Such modifications will become effective on the day they are posted. Car Connectivity encourages you to frequently review the privacy policy for any modifications.  
25390354\V-1

Car Connectivity Consortium LLC ("Car Connectivity " or "We") is committed to user privacy in our products and services. This online privacy policy outlines our information-handling practices for both personal information and non-personally identifiable information for the [www.mirrorlink.com](http://www.mirrorlink.com/) and [www.carconnectivity.org](http://www.carconnectivity.org/) websites (collectively, the “Site” or "Car Connectivity Website"). This policy applies only to transactions with, and information gathered from, the Car Connectivity Website and related services, and does not apply to activities unrelated to the Car Connectivity Website. By using the Car Connectivity Website, you agree to accept the practices and terms set forth in this privacy policy. We encourage you to read this privacy policy and those of all websites that you visit.

For each visitor to Car Connectivity’s Site, Car Connectivity’s Web server may recognize, collect and/or store information such as the visitor’s IP address/domain name combination, and any referring sites to keep track of the origin of our visitors and other non-personally-identifiable information, that will help administer the Car Connectivity Website and to help diagnose any problems that may occur with our server. The non-personally identifiable information we may gather includes the type of browser that you use and IP address, the content that you access and the length of your visit to the Car Connectivity Website. Car Connectivity uses this information, typically in aggregate form, to improve the operation of the Car Connectivity Website and organization, analyze interest in the areas of the Car Connectivity Website and to personalize and similarly tailor content displayed to users. We may also release aggregate information about user trends to partners and other third parties. An example of this type of information would be patterns of use of the Car Connectivity Website based on geography or industry. We also retain aggregated log files of requested content in order to report overall usage and to evaluate user trends. If you wish to be removed from our email reports list, click on the link to “unsubscribe” at the bottom of any message and you will be immediately unsubscribed.

While we do not generally require you to provide us with personally identifiable information in order to visit and use our Site, in order to participate in some activities, such as becoming a Car Connectivity Member or requesting information about Car Connectivity, it is necessary for you to provide this information. Web-based forms on our site may require users to give us contact information (like their name, company, mailing address, email address, and telephone number). We use contact information from these forms to send the user information about Car Connectivity and may follow up with further mailings. We do not collect any personal information, including your email address, without your prior knowledge and consent. Car Connectivity does not sell to advertiser(s) any personally identifying information that you submit. You always have the choice to opt-out of any future mailing. By using this website, you consent to the collection and use of this information as described herein. You may also be asked to provide personally identifiable information in order to use certain portions of the Car Connectivity Website and to obtain maintenance and support from Car Connectivity, if Car Connectivity elects to provide any. This information may include your name, address, telephone number, company and e-mail address. If you do not wish to provide Car Connectivity with any personally identifiable information, you should cease using that portion of the Car Connectivity Website.

### Cookies and other Information Collection

The Car Connectivity Website uses “cookies”. Cookies help provide a better user experience by storing useful information about the user to provide easier access when the user returns, and to enable us to measure which website areas are of greatest interest. Some pages on our Site may use cookies so that we can recall who you are when you revisit the Site or when you fill out a Web application, and will remember you, providing you with easier access to Website user areas, or to track your preferences to improve your Site experience. We may also compile statistical data from data derived from cookies on your use of our Site. You may decline the cookie by modifying the appropriate settings in your Web browser; however, although you will still be able to access our website, please note that disabling cookies may impede you from taking advantage of certain features on the Site.

The Car Connectivity Website may display advertisements from third parties. Third party advertisers decide which ads are shown. These advertisers may use cookies to collect non-personally identifiable information from our Site visitors. Advertisers use this information to target the ads to their audience and to evaluate their impact.

Car Connectivity may use personally identifying information:

To send you notices and updates relating to your membership in Car Connectivity  
To send you news, updates and special offers from Car Connectivity. You may remove yourself from this list at any time by e-mailing us as provided below.  
To manage your account and account access, provide you with support, at our discretion, and to keep track of support requests.  
To enforce intellectual property rights related to the Car Connectivity Specification and Marks

Car Connectivity may disclose personally identifiable information to third parties to: (i) provide technical support, respond to questions, resolve problems and correct errors with regard to the Car Connectivity Website and Car Connectivity Specification; (ii) to offer Certification Program services with regard to the Terminal Mode specification; (iii) to enhance your experience in connection with the Car Connectivity Website and Terminal Mode Specification, and (iv) to enforce Car Connectivity’s Terminal Mode Specification and related Marks. Car Connectivity may also share personally identifiable information with Car Connectivity agents, representatives, contractors, and service providers in order to provide the Car Connectivity Website and related services. By using the Car Connectivity Website you consent to our sharing your personally identifiable information with third parties in connection with delivering the Car Connectivity Website and the content on the Site. Due to our contractual obligations with these third parties and the need to share personally identifiable information to deliver and support the Car Connectivity Website, we may not provide you with the opportunity to opt-out of sharing personally identifiable information with these third parties and still receive complete access to the Car Connectivity Website and related services. Your personally identifiable information may be provided to a third party if Car Connectivity files for bankruptcy, or there is a transfer of the assets or ownership of Car Connectivity, Car Connectivity may also disclose personally identifiable information in order to respond to a subpoena, court order or other such request. Car Connectivity may also provide such personally identifiable information order to comply with law or in response to a law enforcement agency's request, to enforce our privacy policy and end user agreements or to protect the rights, property or safety of the Car Connectivity Website, users of the services and others.

The Car Connectivity Website may offer links to third party sites. Since Car Connectivity does not control or operate these third party websites, we are not responsible for the privacy policies of websites and services to which the Car Connectivity Website may link. If you provide any information to such third parties, different rules regarding the collection and use of your personal information may apply. We strongly recommend that you review such third party's privacy policies before providing any data to them.

Car Connectivity takes appropriate steps to ensure data privacy and security including through various hardware and software methodologies. However, due to the open communication nature of the Internet, we cannot guarantee that communications between you and the Car Connectivity Website, and the Car Connectivity Website and you, will be free from unauthorized access by third parties. Users of the Car Connectivity Website do so at their own risk. Car Connectivity cannot guarantee the security of any information that is disclosed online.

We will use reasonable efforts to comply with this privacy policy and will take prompt corrective action when we learn of any failure to comply with our privacy policy. We sometimes release beta versions of our website and related services, which are further refined before the release of the final version. Because the website and services are still in a test phase, we may not always catch an unintended privacy issue, despite our efforts to do so. As such, we welcome user feedback on any privacy concerns you may have. In light of the above and because of the complex and constantly changing nature of the internet and related technology, Car Connectivity does not guarantee error-free performance under this privacy policy. To the extent permissible under law, Car Connectivity and third parties providing services to you in connection with the Car Connectivity Website, shall not be liable for any incidental, consequential or punitive damages relating to this privacy policy.

Car Connectivity does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. Car Connectivity requests that children under the age of 13 not use the Car Connectivity Website nor submit any personal information to the Car Connectivity Website. Since information regarding children under the age of 13 is not collected, Car Connectivity does not knowingly use or distribute personal information regarding children under the age of 13. If Car Connectivity obtains actual knowledge that it has collected personal information about a child under the age of 13, that information will be immediately deleted from our database.

If you wish to: (i) remove your personally identifiable information from our database in order to stop receiving information from us, (ii) update your personal information, or (iii) have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this website, you can contact:

Car Connectivity Consortium Administration  
3855 SW 153rd Drive  
Beaverton, OR 97006  
USA  
Attention: Car Connectivity Website Administrator  
Email: [admin@carconnectivity.org](mailto:admin@carconnectivity.org)

Car Connectivity reserves the rights to modify its privacy policy at any time and will notify you by posting an amendment to the privacy policy on the Car Connectivity Website. Such modifications will become effective on the day they are posted. Car Connectivity encourages you to frequently review the privacy policy for any modifications.  
25390354\V-1

Car Connectivity Consortium LLC ("Car Connectivity " or "We") is committed to user privacy in our products and services. This online privacy policy outlines our information-handling practices for both personal information and non-personally identifiable information for the [www.mirrorlink.com](http://www.mirrorlink.com/) and [www.carconnectivity.org](http://www.carconnectivity.org/) websites (collectively, the “Site” or "Car Connectivity Website"). This policy applies only to transactions with, and information gathered from, the Car Connectivity Website and related services, and does not apply to activities unrelated to the Car Connectivity Website. By using the Car Connectivity Website, you agree to accept the practices and terms set forth in this privacy policy. We encourage you to read this privacy policy and those of all websites that you visit.

For each visitor to Car Connectivity’s Site, Car Connectivity’s Web server may recognize, collect and/or store information such as the visitor’s IP address/domain name combination, and any referring sites to keep track of the origin of our visitors and other non-personally-identifiable information, that will help administer the Car Connectivity Website and to help diagnose any problems that may occur with our server. The non-personally identifiable information we may gather includes the type of browser that you use and IP address, the content that you access and the length of your visit to the Car Connectivity Website. Car Connectivity uses this information, typically in aggregate form, to improve the operation of the Car Connectivity Website and organization, analyze interest in the areas of the Car Connectivity Website and to personalize and similarly tailor content displayed to users. We may also release aggregate information about user trends to partners and other third parties. An example of this type of information would be patterns of use of the Car Connectivity Website based on geography or industry. We also retain aggregated log files of requested content in order to report overall usage and to evaluate user trends. If you wish to be removed from our email reports list, click on the link to “unsubscribe” at the bottom of any message and you will be immediately unsubscribed.

While we do not generally require you to provide us with personally identifiable information in order to visit and use our Site, in order to participate in some activities, such as becoming a Car Connectivity Member or requesting information about Car Connectivity, it is necessary for you to provide this information. Web-based forms on our site may require users to give us contact information (like their name, company, mailing address, email address, and telephone number). We use contact information from these forms to send the user information about Car Connectivity and may follow up with further mailings. We do not collect any personal information, including your email address, without your prior knowledge and consent. Car Connectivity does not sell to advertiser(s) any personally identifying information that you submit. You always have the choice to opt-out of any future mailing. By using this website, you consent to the collection and use of this information as described herein. You may also be asked to provide personally identifiable information in order to use certain portions of the Car Connectivity Website and to obtain maintenance and support from Car Connectivity, if Car Connectivity elects to provide any. This information may include your name, address, telephone number, company and e-mail address. If you do not wish to provide Car Connectivity with any personally identifiable information, you should cease using that portion of the Car Connectivity Website.

### Cookies and other Information Collection

The Car Connectivity Website uses “cookies”. Cookies help provide a better user experience by storing useful information about the user to provide easier access when the user returns, and to enable us to measure which website areas are of greatest interest. Some pages on our Site may use cookies so that we can recall who you are when you revisit the Site or when you fill out a Web application, and will remember you, providing you with easier access to Website user areas, or to track your preferences to improve your Site experience. We may also compile statistical data from data derived from cookies on your use of our Site. You may decline the cookie by modifying the appropriate settings in your Web browser; however, although you will still be able to access our website, please note that disabling cookies may impede you from taking advantage of certain features on the Site.

The Car Connectivity Website may display advertisements from third parties. Third party advertisers decide which ads are shown. These advertisers may use cookies to collect non-personally identifiable information from our Site visitors. Advertisers use this information to target the ads to their audience and to evaluate their impact.

Car Connectivity may use personally identifying information:

To send you notices and updates relating to your membership in Car Connectivity  
To send you news, updates and special offers from Car Connectivity. You may remove yourself from this list at any time by e-mailing us as provided below.  
To manage your account and account access, provide you with support, at our discretion, and to keep track of support requests.  
To enforce intellectual property rights related to the Car Connectivity Specification and Marks

Car Connectivity may disclose personally identifiable information to third parties to: (i) provide technical support, respond to questions, resolve problems and correct errors with regard to the Car Connectivity Website and Car Connectivity Specification; (ii) to offer Certification Program services with regard to the Terminal Mode specification; (iii) to enhance your experience in connection with the Car Connectivity Website and Terminal Mode Specification, and (iv) to enforce Car Connectivity’s Terminal Mode Specification and related Marks. Car Connectivity may also share personally identifiable information with Car Connectivity agents, representatives, contractors, and service providers in order to provide the Car Connectivity Website and related services. By using the Car Connectivity Website you consent to our sharing your personally identifiable information with third parties in connection with delivering the Car Connectivity Website and the content on the Site. Due to our contractual obligations with these third parties and the need to share personally identifiable information to deliver and support the Car Connectivity Website, we may not provide you with the opportunity to opt-out of sharing personally identifiable information with these third parties and still receive complete access to the Car Connectivity Website and related services. Your personally identifiable information may be provided to a third party if Car Connectivity files for bankruptcy, or there is a transfer of the assets or ownership of Car Connectivity, Car Connectivity may also disclose personally identifiable information in order to respond to a subpoena, court order or other such request. Car Connectivity may also provide such personally identifiable information order to comply with law or in response to a law enforcement agency's request, to enforce our privacy policy and end user agreements or to protect the rights, property or safety of the Car Connectivity Website, users of the services and others.

The Car Connectivity Website may offer links to third party sites. Since Car Connectivity does not control or operate these third party websites, we are not responsible for the privacy policies of websites and services to which the Car Connectivity Website may link. If you provide any information to such third parties, different rules regarding the collection and use of your personal information may apply. We strongly recommend that you review such third party's privacy policies before providing any data to them.

Car Connectivity takes appropriate steps to ensure data privacy and security including through various hardware and software methodologies. However, due to the open communication nature of the Internet, we cannot guarantee that communications between you and the Car Connectivity Website, and the Car Connectivity Website and you, will be free from unauthorized access by third parties. Users of the Car Connectivity Website do so at their own risk. Car Connectivity cannot guarantee the security of any information that is disclosed online.

We will use reasonable efforts to comply with this privacy policy and will take prompt corrective action when we learn of any failure to comply with our privacy policy. We sometimes release beta versions of our website and related services, which are further refined before the release of the final version. Because the website and services are still in a test phase, we may not always catch an unintended privacy issue, despite our efforts to do so. As such, we welcome user feedback on any privacy concerns you may have. In light of the above and because of the complex and constantly changing nature of the internet and related technology, Car Connectivity does not guarantee error-free performance under this privacy policy. To the extent permissible under law, Car Connectivity and third parties providing services to you in connection with the Car Connectivity Website, shall not be liable for any incidental, consequential or punitive damages relating to this privacy policy.

Car Connectivity does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. Car Connectivity requests that children under the age of 13 not use the Car Connectivity Website nor submit any personal information to the Car Connectivity Website. Since information regarding children under the age of 13 is not collected, Car Connectivity does not knowingly use or distribute personal information regarding children under the age of 13. If Car Connectivity obtains actual knowledge that it has collected personal information about a child under the age of 13, that information will be immediately deleted from our database.

If you wish to: (i) remove your personally identifiable information from our database in order to stop receiving information from us, (ii) update your personal information, or (iii) have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this website, you can contact:

Car Connectivity Consortium Administration  
3855 SW 153rd Drive  
Beaverton, OR 97006  
USA  
Attention: Car Connectivity Website Administrator  
Email: [admin@carconnectivity.org](mailto:admin@carconnectivity.org)

Car Connectivity reserves the rights to modify its privacy policy at any time and will notify you by posting an amendment to the privacy policy on the Car Connectivity Website. Such modifications will become effective on the day they are posted. Car Connectivity encourages you to frequently review the privacy policy for any modifications.  
25390354\V-1
